Richard Czechowski

Jr. Web Developer && Philomath

richardczechowski@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a MEAN stack developer who cut his teeth at Coding House and City University of Seattle. In addition to which, I received by BA in Philosophy from UCR.

I specialize in web and app design but also study general software engineering technologies and practices.

Experience

Intern at Daily Steak

March 2014 - Present (9 months)

"Daily Steak" is a audio and video news app which saves people time getting to the news that's truly of interest to them. Viewers have the ability to skip or drill down into news stories and the ability to compare multiple perspectives.

Supervisor at Starbucks

November 2004 - November 2014 (10 years 1 month)

Supervisory duties included: Conducting meetings, supervising up to ten people directly, handling communications, ordering, inventory, customer need triage and much more.

Test Scores

GRE

November 2012 Score:167/159/4.5

Honors and Awards

Oliver Johnson Essay Award

UCR

2012

Award for most outstanding philosophy essay among undergraduate students.

MSRIP

MSRIP

June 2012

Summer research oriented internship. Duties included writing and researching for a philosophy textbook.

Languages

English

German

(Native or bilingual proficiency) (Limited working proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

JavaScript

jQuery

Node.js

MongoDB

AngularJS

HTML 5

CSS3

Responsive Web Design

C#

C++

Unity3D

Git

Bootstrap

CSS

HTML5

Creative Writing

Critical Thinking

Education

Coding House

Certificate, Computer Programming, Specific Applications, 2014 - 2014

Activities and Societies: Hackathon @ NestGSV

City University of Seattle

BSCS, Computer Programming, 2013 - 2014

UC Riverside

Bachelor of Arts in philosophy, German continental philosophy, 2010 - 2012

Richard Czechowski

Jr. Web Developer && Philomath

richardczechowski@gmail.com



Contact Richard on LinkedIn